Let's continue our series about reinforcement learning for animation and this time we will
be looking at a paper that has a continuous state space and a parametrized action space.
So for each action, instead of just being able to play one clip, we will be able to
select several of them and blend them together.
Hi, I'm Jérôme and today's paper is Real Time Planning for Parametrized Human Motion,
a paper from 2008. As usual, what I would do is that I will
import a bunch of libraries I need and I will import my characters,
sets of mesh to represent the direction and the targets.
And what I would do is that for the animation data,
this time instead of using LaFan animations, I would use
Matarica AI website to generate a bunch of locomotion animations.
So the websites allow you fairly easily
to just select the trajectory that you want to see
and then generating animations for it
and to export that animations.
The free tier allows you to generate
up to 10 second of animations.
So a lot enough for what I need to do here.
So what I have is that already a bunch of animations
and that I have retargeted on my character
And so if we check, those clips I have is those ones.
So I got a bunch of turning animations like this
and I will have a few of turn animations
that then start and stop.
So I get 46 different clips like this.
And this paper builds on top of the previous,
a new optimal character animation
with continuous control that we did before.
So it uses exactly the same concept
for slicing your clips into small steps
and realigning all those steps every time.
Those clips every time you want to pick an action
and play the next clip, you align both.
So I will not go through that process again.
It is exactly the same process as the
near optimal character animation
with continuous control paper.
So go watch that video if you want to see
exactly how those clips works.
So the only thing I would do is that I would basically
regenerate all the motion clips and go back to the stage
we were with the previous paper, which is this.
Every clip is something like this, a small step,
and then so you get the first contact next
and that stops there.
So every clip is this and then you will be able to play
with putting them back to back.
So I got a bunch of clips doing all the different rotation
and turns and all of this stuff.
So that's the animation data, is the clips of the animation
data we'll be using.
So what I will have is, as usual,
I will have a player that's allowed me to just say,
I want to play this clip after that one, after that one,
and so on, and so on, and keep track of the positions
and realign all the clips automatically.
So I'll load that code.
And just to show you exactly as before,
what I can do is I can just set the player
to randomly pick a clip every time.
And you get this basically.
It just randomly picks clips
and you can see that it could generate
fairly continuous motion with no foot sliding, except that it might have discontinuities
completely between clips, but the player is still able to do what we were doing in the
previous paper.
And following the exact same system as the previous paper, what we need to compute now
is computing the physical continuity between each clip so basically making sure that
when we pick a motion and we pick a clip after another one it is physically plausible.
Also make sure that we never pick the wrong foot by giving a really high cost of playing a clip
that is on the wrong foot. And I'm also taking that time to compute how much playing a clip after
another one will actually rotate the character and will actually move the character on X and Z
positions. So all this code is exactly the same as the previous paper, no difference here. So
So I've just run it before and I will just reload the stuff that I've created.
So right now I have a big table that gives me the physics costs from any clip to any
other clip.
I get the rotation delta from any clip to any other clip and the same for position X
and Z.
video. We have the exact same features that we had previously. Now, what we want to do
is actually train an optimal policy, trying to match a goal. And the first goal that we're
trying to match is the easy one is to make sure that the character I control goes in
the direction I want him to go. And for this, the paper has it's fairly similar to the continuous
control. It's just take a different approach on the approximations of the value function.
So if you remember the previous one, we were using basis functions to approximate the value
functions. And why we had to do this is because the value function is inside of a continuous space.
So it's hard to train it on every possible values. So what we do is that we train on a subset
and we try to approximate the value function as best as we could with something that will
will give us what we expect the value to be outside of the value we've truly seen.
We did it with basis functions and basically what this is called usually, it's a regression.
So what you have is a function that you don't know, a bunch of points on that functions
that you do compute and you try to regress and find an approximations for the function
itself.
So, basis functions was one way of doing it.
This paper decided to go with extra tree regressors.
And why they've picked it is because it's a known regressor.
It's good at giving you an approximation of any functions when you throw a lot of data
at it. And the advantage of an XF3 regressor compared to the basis functions is that it is
able to approximate anything without a prior knowledge of what the value functions should look
like. If you remember when we did it with basis functions, what happened is that you do have to
to kind of guess what the value function would be
to figure out what is the basis functions you want to use
to address and to approximate them.
Here, you could just throw a regressor at it
and see what it would learn from it.
It has a little higher cost in memory, of course,
because it has more parameters to learn
and memorized and just the few basis functions you could use.
But it's also better at learning a value functions
that will not be extremely smooth.
What happened is basis functions,
we assume that the value functions will be quite smooth
and then we could just use a bunch of Gaussian values
to approximate it.
The regressor, the extractor regressor,
just accept any shape without assuming that it will be smooth or anything. So that's the first
difference between the two papers. They use a different type of regressor. In my case, I will
use the extra tree regressor from sci-pi directly because it exists. I know that it's stable there
and I could just use this one. They do implement their own with some specific mathematics behind it.
I will not go into detail with those, I will just use the regressor.
Okay, let's go through how to train the optimal policy.
It is fairly similar to the previous system.
So what you do is that you start with an empty, but value functions where everything is zero.
So basically you have no knowledge of what the value function will be, set it all to
zero. And you start to create a training set out of all the possible states you could have.
So the way you do it is that you randomly start at any in any states. And from there,
you use your optimal policy to traverse, to start from that states and you just use the
policy and see what you get as a result. And for all the steps you take, so you basically move
forward as if you were playing, and for all of those you store the pair between the states
and the reward that you would get from taking that action.
So you store the states and reward that you encounter while traversing
your states. Once you have all of those,
when you have a set of those, you train your
extra tree regressors to approximate all the value functions.
So you get a new set of value functions and you re-update all your pairs you had.
So basically, you know, you've computed states and rewards, states, rewards, states, reward.
You recompute the value functions and then you go back through all the states you've seen.
You retake the best optimal trajectory you could have taken,
best optimal action you could have taken from there, you get a new reward probably,
and you update the values for each of them. And when you've done this, you start the loop again,
you reset a bunch of random starting positions, walk through and get a few new trajectories
that should probably be better because your value functions get better and better every time,
and you keep repeating this until you get conversions.
What they would do is that they would stop getting new data at some point,
and then they would just train the value functions on itself with all the data they have.
Let's not spend too much time on that detail. But yeah, usually that's how you do it.
It's the loop of getting a bunch of data, training your value functions,
updating all the data you had, get more data and so on and so on until convergence.
And to check that you have converge, we compute the Bellman residual and it's just the computation
of knowing this states expected last time this reward and if I actually take my policy,
it gets that as a reward and you check the difference between the two.
and the goal is to have zero difference to get the expected reward being exactly the reward
you are waiting for.
So that's it, that's how the algorithm will work and now we will train this and see how
we could do it. So I will do it for the example of rotating my character and so the only
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
Why is the reward fairly simple?
Yeah, that's it there.
So the reward is, as before,
is basically I will encode everything
as saying that my character should walk forward
inside of a state space.
So the state space is always local for my character.
And the only thing I want to do is to make it sure
that it walk forward inside of the state space,
say basically anything that tells me that it is an angle
would say that's the offsets,
that's making me not walk in the direction I want it to walk.
So the only thing I compute is the angle
of my character local to itself where it end up walking.
up working. So that's my state say so much rotations offsets I want to have
compared to in front of me. So I will have a transition function that is just
able to say I'm in this clip with a plane on X and Z positions and I get an
angle relative to my plane and I want to play a next clip to that and where
That that will bring me that's basically what it returns me it returns the next clip
Then the next X prime the next Z prime and the next
That are primed the next rotation. So the transitions
Basically is computed the same way as it was done in the continuous state space. I
get the transition reward as
is what is the reward of taking one of the actions?
So basically, if I'm in specific states
and I want to go to the next states,
what is the reward of doing that?
And basically, in this case, the reward is negative,
is the inverse of the cost.
So the bigger the cost,
the more negative that reward is.
And the state reward is just the reward
of being inside of a state itself and a state reward.
What I would do is that I would say anything
that is over the original animation number 25
returns a big negative score.
And that's just because I know that all of my animations
I've done here, as you see, I get the walking and curve,
walking in curve, I get a bunch of turn, I get to walk forward, then everything else
is start, stop, slowing down and stops. So I'm in a controller that's where I just want to
walk in a specific direction. So basically, picking any animation that is not a walking
animation is a big negative reward. And apart from that, where am I here? Otherwise, I just check
where this state will bring me relative to where I want to walk actually and that's it,
they will just return the absolute angle. So if my states make me walk in the direction I want it,
that's basically a reward of zero, otherwise it's a negative reward of how much disalignment you have.
So, fairly stretchable forward for the rewards and that kind of stuff.
What I will have is how to pick, to read my value function compared to the top-primes
and the clip ID.
And here is the stuff that I've done a little differently than the paper.
paper is using an extra three regressor and then it's just using it directly to get the value.
What I wanted to do here, it was to be able to use NumPy and the vectorization of NumPy so I could
basically request the value functions for every states in one go and having all of that computed
in parallel, which is something that is fairly hard to do with the implementation of the
extra tree regressor in scipy. I mean, that's one tree that runs on one core and so on.
So what I've done is that I would compute the value functions, the extra trees regressor,
I will compute all of them. And then once they compute it, I will pre compute a search table.
So basically, I will use the value functions and I will say, that's nice, you have an extra
tree regressor that gives me an approximation. Now just give me a big table of pre-competed
values so I could just pick the closest one. And at least I can do that in parallel for all the
clips in one go. So that's why I have here the value functions actually are not the trees exactly.
they are one big table with a bunch of pre-competed values for me. And so that
allows me to find easily old indices that I want to search inside of
that table and then to return the values of that table. And I use optimal
policy then basically is just taking the starting clip I have and picking the
transitions from the starting clip towards all the clips at once so taking
taking the transition between my clip and everything else that's giving me the
x prime z prime and theta prime of all the possible transitions then I compute
transition rewards for all those different transitions. And I can compute the future reward
for all of them again, multiplying by the discount factor. And once I have that,
I just pick the one that has the highest score. And then what I return is the picked one, the new
x prime z prime theta prime and the reward and this time in the reward I picked the
the transitions plus the future reward so that's basically the future reward
and I'm adding the state reward to it because that state reward doesn't change anyway it's
the reward of being in my state now not the reward of being in any future state or anything
And so that's the value functions and the policy itself.
I will not care about this one.
And so what happened is now I could do the algorithm of trying to train that value function.
And see, it's done the way the paper describes it.
basically I take height 100 random starting positions so I picked randomly any clip and
I picked randomly any angle and that becomes my state so one clip one angle that's my state
and then from that state I use my optimal policy to get the next clip and I store
I store my state in the X so I store my current clip and data and I store the associated reward
for it and I keep this for 10 steps. I keep walking using my optimal policy for 10 steps
and recording every pair of state reward and once I have that pairs of state reward
I train for each of my clip I will train an extra tree regressor. So it's the
same concept as the continuous character control. You have one value function per
clip. So basically it is a continuous state space where the clip itself is
tabulated. So you learn a bunch of continuous state space next to each
other and a bunch of value functions next to each other. So each clip has its own value function
into a continuous value functions and then you train all of them at the same time.
So because you will start from one clip and read the value functions of the other one and so on.
So you have to train all of them at once, consider them as one big value functions
except the clips are tabulated. So compute the extractor regressor with all the pairs of states
and reward. And as I said, what I do after that is that I predict a bunch of values because that
is again vectorized and parallelized fairly well. So I can predict, I think I predict 300
different values for each of my trees. And I put all of that into one big table,
so I will be able to use NumPy to do computation in parallel on that big table.
And so once you've done this, what you do is computing the residual. So how much errors
you have between what reward I was expecting before and what reward I receive now that I've
updated my value functions and at the same time I update the expected return to be the new
expected reward basically. So that's the expected reward for the next iteration now
has been updated with the new rewards I have now. Again, I've run this before and I will just reload
what I've loaded and what you could see is that I haven't done a lot of epoch because basically
it's fairly easy to learn in this case. What you see is the mean error, the mean residual,
Bellman residual, so it drops fairly quickly and I get the maximum residual error, so also
dropping between the best expected reward and what I actually get. I don't have a lot of difference.
And so I can now have a gamepad and I can start to play with what we've learned
here. And so now every time I write it, it will just use the same optimal policy of checking
every possible clip, checking the future reward to see how good this gets. And so we have something
that is fairly close to the continuous control except that I would agree that
using the extractory regressor was a lot simpler to use than trying to find what
would be the best basis functions for the for the value functions and it's
it's quite responsive. You could tweak if you wanted to learn something a bit more responsive
and by giving less score to the physicality continuity, but it does work.
Now, what this paper shows is that learning with extra tree regressor was needed if they
wanted to do, in that case they were doing grabbing animations, so giving an object asks
the character to move toward that object and grabbing it.
I don't have graphing animations so what I would do instead is stopping at a specific
target. So I will give him targets somewhere in the world and I want the character to walk
toward the target and stopping on the target. It basically gives the same concept, maybe
a little less visual but it's still working. So what I will have is what I call the reach goal
policy. So I have a bunch of animations that are stopping animations. So I know
which one they are. So that's all my stopping clips. Those one were just the
two stops, two-step stops at the end. Now the only thing I need is to know, you know,
I will ask it to stop at a specific position, which means that by the time
take the decision I need to make sure that take the decision that if I play that clip it would
stop where I want it to be so I need to know what is the state in which I need to be to actually
make sure that if I play that stop I will stop where I want it so that's the stop positions
it's basically give me where I actually need to be when I take that decision to play this clip
so it would just finish the animation in the right spot, so I compute basically why the stop
needs to be starting to stop at zero zero zero. Now the reward function for this system normally
is this. As they said, you basically give it just a reward. If you are stopping on the right spot,
you get a reward of one. And every time you do not, your reward is zero.
basically that's a sparse reward function so it means that there is a really not a lot of time
something that gives you a reward so they say in the paper that you could just train with this
reward functions and that would work and that's magic it's something that is known to be extremely
hard to train actually. And with the data I have was not able to just hope for the best like they
were saying and then make it work. Because what happened is that you have two cases basically
and you have to find the right balance between the two. If your reward from reaching a certain
position is really big. What happens is that it would transfer that value through your value functions
through every state near it. So everything will say it's really important for me to reach that
point. I don't care if the transition cost is really high, if all my feet are sliding,
if I pick the wrong clip, as long as I'm reaching that reward, that's what matters.
So that's what happens if you give your reward for reaching a value that's too high.
On the other hand, if your reward value is too small, basically what the system will
learn is that everything is bad anyway.
There is no reward of walking more in that direction than anything else.
So what it will learn at the end is that as long as everything is negative anyway, let's
pick the one that gives a nice continuous animation and I don't care if I reach the goal or not
and you really need to fight between those two and it's really hard to find the right values
that will actually let you but let the value functions learn exactly how to get there especially
because in my case I have 200 clips I think and I only have a few stops so really not a lot of
stopping clips. So it's really sparse in my case. So I was not able to train my value functions
just by doing this. So there is a bunch of tricks you could apply when you try to train
a sparse value functions like that one. So what I would have to do to train these value functions,
I would not be able to just let it hope that you will find something
by just stumbling upon one positive values and then hoping that it will
start to learn that maybe going that direction is the good way. So what I
would do is that I will add a bunch of tricks that you could use when you try
to train values like this one that has a release pass reward. The first thing you
could do is to have a bootstrap. So basically instead of starting from
nothing start from something that's not it works. So what I would do is that I will give him a bunch
of known trajectories that are actually reaching the goal and I'm starting from those trajectories
instead of starting from nothing. That's the first thing. The second thing I realized that I needed
was the fact that although it was able to find the target when he was fairly in the certain
area around it, when he was too far from it, I had nothing that was forcing him to to walk back
in the right direction. So I would also add a penalty of being too far away from the goal.
So basically, it would force the system to say, if I'm really far, it's better that I walk in the direction of the goal.
And as soon as close enough, I will find the best trajectory to reach the goal anyway.
But I actually had to have those two different costs.
One that's trying to get to the goal and one that's really far, you try to walk towards mainly the goal.
And then the last thing I've done is instead of telling the system that I want him to...
Every time I get the new reward instead of setting that value for the new reward,
I was using a temporal difference.
So I'm only computing the error I have between the expected reward I wanted and the true reward I wanted.
want it. And I'm only slightly updating the expected reward.
Instead of just replacing it, I just said, I take 10% of the new reward, and I love 10%
of that new reward. And that's how I managed to make this learn.
So basically, the transition functions is a bit different, because before everything
was local to my character and I was telling them the character that it has to
work forward and that's it and I was computing the angle. This time every
state's encode in the position X and Z where the target is. So if my character
is here and the target is here that's what it's encoded. If it works like this
basically the new values is this offset. So everything is always realigned
to the character. So my target is always represented as a local offset from my character. So I get my
transition. What I will have is an inverse transition functions basically computing the
exact opposite of this one saying that if I'm now in a specific states and I was coming from
another state. Where was I? That's what the transition inverse does.
I get the transition reward, same as before. It's the physical costs and inverse the physical costs.
And I get the state reward. And the only thing that the state rewards does is this. If I'm
playing a stop animation, I'm just checking am I in a radius of 50
centimeters around where I wanted him to stop and if it's the case you get a
reward of one and if you ever pick that state reward with that stopping
animations while you actually do not stop in the right spot you get the
massive negative reward, saying that that was not what I wanted you to do. Never stops outside of
your stopping animation. And that's why I, for all the other cases, if I'm really far from my goal,
I get a little penalty from being too far. That's it. That's my state reward. I still get my value
functions instead of now it's an x and z value functions the 2d value function and my optimal
policy it's basically the same optimal policy as before i take my transitions i get the transition
reward i read the value functions i get the value functions for it and i picked the best one the
only thing i did just to avoid having those massive negative values getting injected inside of the
value functions. What I've done is that if I realized that it picked a stopping animation
while it shouldn't have anyway, basically restart the search for the optimal policy
by removing any stopping animations from the the available clip you can look at. So basically,
I'm checking every clip, if it decided that the best clip it could pick was a stopping
animation while it wasn't supposed to stop, I just tell him search again, this time doesn't
count for the stopping animations.
So that's the value of functions.
Now I do need to do that bootstrap.
basically what I have is a system that's allowed me to roll back trajectories. I can say I'm starting
from one position and I walk backwards from there. That's what the rollback trajectory will do.
And so for instance, let's pick this one. I get all the my stopping animations and I will roll back
eight steps and you can see basically there's a kind of stuff I will start the
learning from you know I have all those different trajectories that will
eventually anyway stop all in the same position so that's that's what the the
bootstrapping would do I will have all of those trajectories pre-generated and
I can start to learn from those. So I will not run this because it would take a bunch of time.
I will do this 100 times different positions for all the stops. So it would generate
100,000 different trajectories that actually reach the end.
Oh, I can do it. So I can show you what happens. I don't think it's that long. So
So I generate a lot of trajectories, yeah.
And then I can display now all the, for every clip animation,
you could see all those areas, all positions
that I know that if I'm in that state,
I'm able to reach the stopping animations.
So it gives me a lot of data to start from.
I have a bunch of data that I know that are good enough to start learning from.
And so hopefully it means that every other clips would start to try to reach those points or
another points further and I can stuff and then I would be able to train.
The only difference this time is because it's a lot longer, there is a lot more value functions
and a lot more data in all the value functions. So the only thing I've done to speed up the
process is that I've started a multiprocessing, so I will actually train the value functions
in a pool. So I will actually use all my cores and all my CPUs to train it. But
that's not really important. Everything else is basically the same. You know, I'm
bootstrapping with a bunch of known trajectories that are valid with an
expected, the best expected reward I could get from it. Anyway, it's even higher
because it doesn't take the transition cost into account and then generating a bunch of new paths
and then you stops every time you actually reach the goal you stop because you don't want to see
what happened after the fact that you reached the goal. So train the values and it's the same
loop when I'm training the values, creating the pre-computed tables and
reusing them and then recomputing the residual and all that kind of stuff.
Again, all of that has been run before and I can show you here what happened with
the score and the mean value. So, for every epoch, so I run it 50 epoch this
time. The only thing I've done also, yeah I've done a lot of stuff to make that able to learn.
You can see that it started to learn and so basically at every epoch it's generating it's
around 2600 different trajectories and that's the number of trajectories that actually reached
the goal in 10 steps while learning. You can see that it was starting to get better but it was fairly
slow so after 10 generations what I did is basically I kept the same value function
but I made him forget all the previous trajectory he did and I make him restart again and you can
can see that it suddenly gets a big jump because it has less
example of wrong trajectories.
And so I guess the value functions are softer and better
at learning the values that don't have too much.
And I tried to do it several times,
make him forget again.
And basically, it capped at the same level every time.
So it nearly reached 100%, meaning I can start from anywhere
and in 10 steps, it's always able to reach the stop.
And I can display one of the value functions,
for instance.
So you could see what the value functions look like.
So the pre-computed one goes from minus 1,000 to 1,000.
And you get that there, not exactly in the middle,
a bit offsets.
That's where it wants that clip to be able to reach the stops.
And again, I can play this.
So right now, it's not input anymore.
It will randomly pick a position and try
to get that character to walk toward that goal.
And it has 50 centimeters rear that I
agreed to not trying to make it get perfectly on the stop.
Because, again, those clips are not perfect.
So I want to make sure that it's still
able to reach the end goal easily by giving him
a bit of slack, let's say.
And with all the tricks to train those value functions,
It is then possible to do it.
Without all those added stuff on top of the paper,
I'm not sure I would have been able to learn
these value functions to do this.
Now, that's the default system.
It basically used the exact same thing
as the continuous functions now.
I'm just playing one clip and that's it.
Pick the best clip to reach a goal every time.
What the paper says is that what you have now
is a suboptimal search because it is linked
to all the clip it has and is not able
to learn something a bit more smooth
that would be able to reach more easily the goal.
so comes into play the motion groups so what they have
what they decided to do is this instead of picking one clip
what you do is that you regroup those clips together and that's what they've done here
see they get a bunch of groups and those groups will become your clip.
And inside of those groups you have a bunch of animations that represent the same kind of stuff
and that those animations can be blended together so you could choose to blend between
your first animation and the second one and to have all the in-betweens.
So that's what the motion groups will be here. That would be exactly the same thing. I would
take a bunch of indices and I would take a bunch of weights to decide how they
that represents the blend between the two.
And then I can show an example by picking,
so basically I picked a bunch of indices like that
and a bunch of weights and you can see that what I have
here is the same as before.
You know, I have one clip that is able to do this,
but then I can actually start to blend
and it will be a bit different and you could choose the different blend weights
between the different clips and so now what you end up with is what they
called the parametrized action space because now my action is not just the
clip I had, it is the fact that each of my clips have different possible values.
They have one parameter that decides how much you can tweak them.
So now I actually need to build the same system as what they've done here. So
regrouping all the animations together, that do make sense. And for this I had to write a bunch
of helpers functions to compute the different angle of each of them and all that kind of stuff
to regroup them and by playing all of those I've ended up with this list of motion group indices.
So now those two indices become one motion group from which I can blend between the two.
Those three become one motion group and I can blend between the two animations and so on and so on.
it was basically built by hand in the same way as what they've done.
They're also saying that every clip was chosen by hand and blended by hand.
And now that I have those motion clips, what I would do is define a bunch of weights
for them depending of if I have two indices or three indices I will decide the weights on how I
want to blend them and again why I would do this is because what the paper does
normally it picks one of the motion group and it treats the motion group as
as one action that you can pick.
And so what you do is that the algorithm works as before.
You pick the clip, except that what they've done
as once you've picked the clip,
you actually evaluate the parameterized version
X amount of time.
So you slice it and you take the value of zero one
and then one zero and all in the between
you can choose how many between C1 and you pick the best parametrized version you could have.
You pick the best group and out of that group you re-evaluate your value functions
X amount of time to pick the best parameter you could have. What I would do would be the same
thing except that, again, I want to be able to parallelize all of that with numpy.
So I would go the opposite way. From all my groups, I would, in advance,
parametrize all of them. So I will have, I don't remember how many groups I have,
but I have a bunch of groups and for all of those groups, I would take 11 samples in between.
So I would parametrize all those groups and I would flatten all the list of parametrized
groups in advance. Which is what I'm doing here with the group count. That returns the number
of parametrized versions of the groups I have. So I have now basically 847s
different clip I can pick from because that's basically what it is it's all
the different group with all the different parameters version of the group
itself while I had only 150 clips in the beginning so I'm growing the action
space basically and then I can display all those groups I have so that means
that I get this animation for group 0 and I can see parametrized between those two.
I get that and that's all the different parametrized versions I have.
So I get all my actions now, my animations are slightly parametrized.
What I would do is again I would need to compute the cost of any parametrized version towards
any other parameterized version. So basically that's the reason why I flattened everything in
the beginning because I would need to compute the physics costs between all of the cases.
What they do is they probably compute it at runtime only for the small groups that they know
that they want to stay in. Again I will flatten everything in advance and I will compute everything
in advance. And then the learning is all the same system. What I have is all my stop indices,
except now it's a bunch of stop indices that were parameterized with different lengths,
different stops. So I have a lot more different stops. Again, I will have a lot more standing
position for all those steps. And same way, I would also need to bootstrap my learning
with a bunch of trajectories that I know works. This time, instead of having a lot of random
positions around it and growing only a few paths, what I would do, because I have a lot more possible
trajectories to start from. I will only pick one but I will spread it a lot more. So I would say
I'm starting from here and instead of picking the best trajectory you give me the 20 best
trajectories starting from there and then only growing a lot less further than that. So instead
Instead of having a bunch of long trajectories now, I have a lot of really small ones.
And hopefully I'm still able to learn my value functions, right?
That's what I wanted to get.
I will not run this code because that is a lot longer.
And all the optimal trajectories and all of that stays exactly the same as before.
It's only my optimal policy now and it's a bit different.
And it's only different for one little case, is that before when I was getting my value
function I had one value function per clip.
Now I have one value function per motion group, that was the idea.
You have one, you find the best motion group itself and from that one you picked the best
parametrized version. So because I've pre-flattened everything, what I have now is that
it means that I only need to evaluate the value function.
Well, I need to evaluate the same value functions for all my parametrized versions. So that's what
I'm doing here. That's why I have that weird clip that says group count and then the clip value
functions, which is divided by 11, because I know that I've parameterized 11 times each of them.
So they're grouped like this. And I just need to say, okay, all those values, all those values
need to check that value functions, all those values need to check that value functions,
and so on, so on. So that's the only difference between this version and the other versions,
that a bunch of actions share the same the same value function.
And so I need to run that.
And apart from that, learning process is basically the same thing.
I've trained it several times, I've tweaked a bunch of values by keeping the same value
functions.
So the only thing you see here in the epoch and the score of epoch and that stuff is the
last time I trained the value functions because basically I trained it with the old one and
I reduced, I think the, now I made it learn really close and then started to make it learn
further and further and further to make sure that it starts to reach.
And that's what you see now is the latest run, latest learn. And you could see that
it basically at every iterations it adds 800 something, so it doesn't seem number as group.
So again, always able to find the spot in less than 10 steps more or less.
And I can let it play and we can see what happens now.
So basically, this time, if I let him run, that would be better.
It should be better at stopping on the spot because that's what I've learned him.
I did not give him that big range of possible actions to pick from.
He tries to stop exactly in the spot.
Now you could see that sometimes he does big steps to reach it and that's probably because
I gave him a bunch of trajectories.
instead of finding the best closest one it finds one of the trajectories that
will bring him back where it wanted to be but that's in a nutshell how it works
it has a hard time finding the spot when it's too close if it if it walked just
next to it you would have to do around and come back because there is not
enough, a parametrized version to make short steps and that kind of stuff. But it reaches
more easily the targets we want them to reach. So this is the parametrized version,
so continuous state space and parametrized action space that this paper gives us. I
I hope you liked it and see you next time.